# **Rob Bednark**

Software Engineering Manager

971-276-8789 rbednark@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/robbednark Portland, OR

#### **SUMMARY**

4 years experience as software engineering manager, 3 years as team lead, 17 years as software engineer. I focus on solutions, and meet challenges head-on with empathy and compassion, playing the roles of strategist, leader, engineer, and coach.

I believe people-centered work cultures increase employee happiness, resulting in more productive, creative, and sustainable workplaces, and that human interaction (listening, collaborating, encouraging, conflict-resolution, ...) is essential. I'm down to earth, practical, and pragmatic, bringing ideas out of the clouds and into concrete goals and plans.

### **SKILLS**

Management coaching, compensation, conflict resolution, hiring, mentoring, performance reviews, project

management

Languages Python, JavaScript, Ruby, SQL

Databases ElasticSearch, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Solr

Tools, ... Amazon API-Gateway/AWS/DynamoDB/EC2/Lambda/S3/SES, BuildKite, Django,

Docker, Git, Grafana, GraphQL, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Node, React, Rails, Splunk, Terraform

Methodologies agile, CI/CD, DevOps, kanban, microservices, MVC, OO, scrum, TDD

OS Linux, macOS, Windows

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineering Manager - Invoca / fully remote - 03/2021 - 08/2023

Managed a full-stack development team of 6 direct reports that added new features and maintained multiple functional areas of the platform. Responsibilities:

- Managed direct reports: hired and determined promotions and raises, weekly 1:1s, quarterly performance reviews, set expectations and addressed performance issues, conflict resolution, personal development plans, managed interns
- Project management: coordinated with architects, product managers, lead developers, and UX designers to plan
  and deliver projects; kept the team focused; assigned roles; mitigated risk and delays; created plans-of-action;
  created roadmaps (features and technical initiatives)
- Technical: reviewed code, requirements, UX & technical designs; coding; 24/7 on-call; diagnosed issues
- Tech stack: Ruby on Rails, React, Graphql, Apollo, MySQL, Kubernetes, Redis, Kafka, Grafana, Kibana, BuildKite, AWS, Terraform

# **↑ Sabbatical 02/2020 - 02/2021**

After Moovel announced its shutdown, took a sabbatical to spend time with family and friends, reflect, establish
healthy daily habits (meditating, pairing, running, journaling, stretching), learn new technologies, and work on apps.

Software Engineering Manager, Senior Software Engineer - Moovel / Portland, OR - 11/2016 - 02/2020

#### **Software Engineering Manager**

 Directly responsible for hiring, employee reviews, coordinating with product managers and account executives, product delivery, 24/7 on-call duty, and team health for two cross-functional development teams of six and seven direct reports.

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

- Created designs and specifications for new features
- Worked on back-end services (Python, Django, Node, Jenkins, docker, MySQL, Postgres, ElasticSearch, Redis, Splunk, Jenkins, automated testing (unit, functional, integration))

1

2024-01-02

Implemented a web app for viewing and updating catalog data involving many tables and relationships, with
journaling and workflows (React, Redux, html, CSS, JavaScript)

## TEAM LEAD, SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - Idealist / Portland, OR - 09/2015 - 07/2016

- 20 engineers, developed high-traffic job board website, 2 million visits per month, 1 million users, 100k paying customers
- Converted site to a front-end / RESTful API architecture.
- Implemented an API for external customers to post jobs.
- Very collaborative development environment, with extensive pair programming and mob programming.
- Tech stack: Python (Flask, SQLAlchemy, RabbitMQ), PostgreSQL, Redis, HAProxy, nginx, gunicorn, Bamboo, Lambda, API Gateway, DynamoDB, Linux.

# Senior Platform Engineer - Trapit / Portland, OR - 04/2014 - 08/2015

- Multi-tenanted cloud platform; RESTful API for web and mobile clients
   Services to continuously pull content from 100k+ RSS feeds into multiple databases, sending email, and getting social media share analytics
- Emphasized performance, scalability, automated testing, and reliability.
- 100k+ RSS feeds, 10k users, 80 enterprise customers, 30 services, and used 100+ PyPI python packages and standard libraries.
- Tech stack: AWS, boto S3, Cassandra, fabric, Linux, nginx, NoSQL, ORM, pillow, pipelines, PostgreSQL, puppet, pystache, RabbitMQ, Redis, RSS, SES, Solr, SQL, SQLAlchemy, zmg

# Software Architect, Lead Software Engineer - Atlatl Software / Portland, OR - 01/2013 - 04/2014

- Employee #10 in a 30-person startup
- Software architect and team lead for web application, API's, and database
- Grew from 2 to 8 engineers; team lead for 7 engineers (3 local, 4 outsourced in Vietnam).
- When I started, software was still in development, and I was actively involved with deploying the project into
  production for multiple tenants. Championed test automation, code reviews, requirements, architectural designs,
  configurable features, technical documentation, performance, hiring excellent engineers, automatic test data
  generation, and logging.
- Tech stack: Django, Python, PostgreSQL, Selenium, factory\_boy, Linux, Nginx, Memcached, AWS, Sentry, JSON, test-driven development (TDD)

### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - Tixie / Portland, OR - 06/2012 - 01/2013

- Added functionality to the web app, including user registration and profiles, and created processes to calculate and update data.
- Tech stack: Python, Django, Amazon AWS/EC2/S3/SES, Celery, CSS, Fabric, factory\_boy, HTML, Linux, Memcached, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, Sentry, South, SQL

# QA Lead (contract) - Uncorked Studios / Portland, OR - 08/2011 - 09/2011

- Led the QA effort for a high-profile iOS, Android, Mobile Web, and web app.
- Features included Facebook sharing, geocoding, reverse geocoding, geotagging, 2D/3D virtual-reality mapping; upload, display, and playback of video, audio, photo, and text.

# QA Manager (contract) - Huawei / remote - 12/2010 - 07/2011

Managed the QA for social-networking web app and mobile apps with VoIP, chat, email, and address book features.

2

- Managed team; recruited and hired; wrote test plan, testcase specifications, monitoring tool and automated tests.
- Remote team across 13 sites in the U.S., England, Ukraine, Russia, and India.
- Oversaw test automation utilizing Selenium, Python, nose, Ruby, Capybara, and Cucumber.

### **EARLIER EXPERIENCE**

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - IBM

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - INFORMIX

Software Engineer - Milner, Inc.

## **EDUCATION**

ST. CLOUD STATE UNIVERSITY St. Cloud, MN

B.S. Computer Science, Human Relations minor Honors Program

2024-01-02